# Mohammed Moataz

Giza, Egypt +20 100 858 1523

**Gmail:** 

imohammedmoataz@gmail.com LinkedIn: mohammed-moataz **Github:** MohammedMoataz Website: mohammed.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Resourceful software engineer with both front-end and back-end development experience. Smart and consistently educated designer of user interactions on sound and user-friendly websites and databases. Proven troubleshooting with a solid grounding in data-driven concepts and applications.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### <u>Catch Code</u>, Giza— Software Engineer

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

- Augmented with the backend team to develop APIs using Node.JS
- Collaborated to develop the desktop application using JavaFX.
- Analyzed, prioritized, and problem-solved several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.

## **CBMIS**, Remotely—Software Engineer Trainee

Jun 2022 - Jan 2023

- Learned new emerging technologies.
- Analyzed, prioritized, and problem-solved several tasks.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence Helwan University**, Cairo — *Very Good*

September 2019 - July 2023.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Concepts** 

OOP / Data Structures / Design Patterns / Restful APIs / GraphQL

Development

BlockChain / Java Spring / Node.JS / React.JS

#### **SKILLS**

Adaptability.

Teammates' Motivation

Problem-Solving.

Fast learning.

Teamwork.

Good Listener.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Google IT Support, Google

Dec 2022

Agile Scrum, ODC

Sep 2022

ITI Java Spring Developer, ITI

Sep 2022

Web Design, NTI

Aug 2022

**Google Project Management** 

Specialization, Google

Jun 2022

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic

English

Database

MySQL / MongoDB / Firestore

Tools

Docker / Git / Jira / Trello

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

# Google Developers Student Club - Helwan University

2022 Technical Head.

- Flutter Instructor.
- Responsible for How-To workshops. 2021 Technical Core Team Member.

Data Structures Instructor.

# Online - Helwan University

2022 Vice president.

2019 Media team member.